Seth Messer

1926 Cahaba Cove Hoover, AL 35244 (205) 541-4363 seth@megalithic.io twitter.com/megalithic github.com/megalithic megalithic.io

My ability to build all things, both physical and digital, is not only my passion, but is what drives me to succeed. Even after 2 decades of delivering quality production software, I am constantly honing my skills while striving to foster growth in those around me.

Education

1997 - 2002

Auburn University, Auburn, AL - Bachelor's of Industrial and Product Design

Experience

AUG 2021 - JAN 2023

Outstand, Remote - Senior Software Engineer

- Worked as a Senior Software Engineer focused on Elixir to deliver quality software to production with a delightful user experience.
- Completed day-to-day project requirements of adding new features/supporting client requests and support requests for our platform built on Rails.
- Spearheaded a green-field initiative for the next generation of platform, built upon Elixir
 and Phoenix LiveView. I built an analytics dashboard that interacted with our existing
 MySQL databases and our Elasticsearch instances to query/generate interactive metrics
 and graphs using VegaLite.
- Collaborated with the product and design team to build out the front-end using Phoenix components and Tailwind from Figma mockups and design system..
- Built debt calculator and customer engagement applications for financial management clients using Elixir and Phoenix LiveView.
- Maintained our Ruby/Rails platform, in addition to several ancillary applications built in Elm,
 Typescript + WebComponents, Backbone, Ember, and a React Native mobile application.
- Mentored one of the junior engineers.

JAN 2021 - AUG 2021

Generac Grid Services (née Enbala), Remote - Software Engineering Manager

- Built and fostered relationships with employees to help them achieve their goals technically and professionally.
- Worked with the Manager of Agile Practices to help create and maintain a positive work culture.
- Acted as the primary hiring manager for the engineering team.

• Helped navigate Enbala's engineering team through the acquisition by Generac.

OCT 2018 - JAN 2021

Generac Grid Services (née Enbala), Remote - Software Engineer

- Worked across scrum teams at various capacities on an umbrella Elixir codebase and the Elm front-end (the entirety of the front-end was built in Elm).
- Traveled to Krakow, Poland, to onboard a contracting team in Enbala's methodologies, architecture and SDLC.
- Managed the team for iteration-to-iteration software delivery
- Mediated communication between Enbala leadership and the contractors project management team.

MAR 2018 - OCT 2018

RE/MAX LLC (née First), Remote - Senior Software Engineer

- Worked in both the web application and React Native-based mobile application to provide an excellent user experience to real estate agents, aiding them in fostering new and existing relationships to turn those relationships into sales.
- Utilized TypeScript, React, React Native, and apollo-graphql; as well as Ruby on Rails for the back-end.

MAY 2017 - MAR 2018

Eezy.com, **Remote** – *Senior Software Engineer*

 Maintained a legacy online vector editor app (Vecteezy), built in WebComponents with a focus on SVG. Lead the effort to completely rewrite Vecteezy in React/Redux built upon Fabric.js.

FEB 2015 - MAY 2017

Welltok, Inc., Remote - Senior Software Engineer

- Focused on front-end development, inside a React/Redux/Node/Ruby on Rails stack.
- Acted as one of the core creators and contributors of our front-end stack, dubbed Voltron.js.
- Contributed to Welltok's node-based CLI package a robust suite of utilities aiding in deployment and maintenance.
- Mentored several junior, QA, and contract engineers.
- Helped build Welltok's engineering onboarding processes.

FEB 2012 - FEB 2015

Isotope11, **Birmingham**, AL - *Software Engineer*

- Provided the highest level of craftsmanship, knowledge, and production development experience to clients, clients' users, and peers..
- Worked in a range of tech stacks, including JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and Java.
- Clients included: the U.S. Government Accountability Office (GAO)/FedAPI, United States
 Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), Cricket

- Wireless formerly Aio Wireless, TruCoin RT, Learning Earnings, Doodlebugs Daily, and isotope11.com.
- Utilized a multitude of JavaScript frameworks to complete projects (as requirements dictated), such as Dojo, Angular, jQuery, and vanilla JavaScript.
- Used TDD where possible Jasmine, Chai, DOH and Capybara with MiniTest for integration tests in Ruby.
- Handled many of the iterative UI design duties, and the resulting semantic, standards-based HTML and CSS.

MAR 2008 - OCT 2012

Influence Health (née Medseek), Birmingham, AL - Interaction Developer

- Development software using ASP.net, C#, and JavaScript.
- Worked with solutions and product management to develop business requirements into workable UI/UX solutions.
- Helped define design patterns and front-end development standards for a more consistent user experience and interface design.
- Worked primarily on MEDSEEK's flagship ASP.net/C# product to build
- Provided front-end support to the other developers.
- Trained them on CSS and standards-based markup best practices, especially as it pertained to ASP.net webforms controls (pre-ASP.net MVC).

MAR 2006 - MAR 2008

FIS (née SunGard), Birmingham, AL - Front-End Engineer

- Focused on front-end development, in addition to working with our clients in a solutions analysis and gathering role.
- Worked with a team in Blacksburg, Virginia that was focused primarily on a document imaging and recognition product called FormWorks.
- Provided front-end development support for the team as they transitioned the application from a legacy Winforms solution to an ASP.net web application.

2004 - MAR 2006

InLine, Birmingham, AL - Web Developer

- Handled most of the graphic design and web design needs for internal and client projects
- Developed skills in ASP.net with C# and VB.net by working on internal applications, such as an asset management web app, and a class-action lawsuit management web app.
- Designed and developed the online renewal application for the Alabama Plumbers and Gas
 Fitters Examining Board using ASP.NET, C# and SQL Server.
- Designed and developed Express Oil Change's public-facing website.

2002 - 2004

AL.com, Birmingham, AL - Ad and Web Designer

- Worked as a website ad designer (using Adobe Photoshop),
- Built and maintained client websites in PHP, HTML, JavaScript and CSS.